<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nfjs on Matt Stine</title>
    <link>https://www.mattstine.com/categories/nfjs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nfjs on Matt Stine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Matt Stine</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mattstine.com/categories/nfjs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>nfjs fall 2010 what do you want to learn</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstine.com/2010/06/22/nfjs-fall-2010-what-do-you-want-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattstine.com/2010/06/22/nfjs-fall-2010-what-do-you-want-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone! I&amp;rsquo;m currently in the process of developing new talks for my Fall 2010 NFJS tour dates. While I don&amp;rsquo;t know yet where I&amp;rsquo;ll be speaking, I can tell you that I&amp;rsquo;ve registered availability for the following shows:
 Boston, MA
 Seattle, WA
 Atlanta, GA
 Minneapolis, MN
 Chicago, IL
 Denver, CO
  So, if you&amp;rsquo;re in one of those cities and you&amp;rsquo;re thinking about attending NFJS when it comes your way (see here for the schedule), I&amp;rsquo;d like to know what you want to hear about assuming I come your way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>career 20 toastmasters</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstine.com/2009/05/11/career-20-toastmasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattstine.com/2009/05/11/career-20-toastmasters/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently making my second trip through Jared Richardson&amp;rsquo;s excellent book Career 2.0: Take Control of Your Life. In the &amp;ldquo;Public Speaking&amp;rdquo; chapter, one of the recommended avenues for public speaking practice is Toastmasters. I first heard of Toastmasters&amp;hellip;you guessed it, on my first trip through the book. Shortly after returning home from NFJS St. Louis, I decided to see if I could find a local club. Lo and behold, a Toastmasters club already meets on the St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on our way to the gateway software symposium</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstine.com/2008/02/08/on-our-way-to-the-gateway-software-symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattstine.com/2008/02/08/on-our-way-to-the-gateway-software-symposium/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re taking most of our team to the St. Louis, Missouri, edition of the No Fluff Just Stuff 2008 tour. This will be my first actual NFJS event. I attended the Spring Experience in 2007, which was put on by the NFJS guys, so I expect this event in St. Louis to be great. Since we&amp;rsquo;re based in Memphis, St. Louis is only about a 4 1&amp;frasl;2 hour drive. We&amp;rsquo;re all going to pile in a van and road trip.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>