<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jsf on Matt Stine</title>
    <link>https://www.mattstine.com/categories/jsf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jsf on Matt Stine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Matt Stine</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mattstine.com/categories/jsf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>how to implement form level validation in jsf</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstine.com/2007/06/27/how-to-implement-form-level-validation-in-jsf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattstine.com/2007/06/27/how-to-implement-form-level-validation-in-jsf/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was faced with the challenge of implementing form-level (or page-level) validation in a JSF-based application. What I mean by form-level validation is the need to evaluate a subset of a form&amp;rsquo;s fields as a unit, rather than simply validating each field in isolation. An example of this type of validation can be found on a user registration form where one has to select a password in one text field, and then retype the same password in another text field for confirmation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>thursday was slow</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstine.com/2007/05/11/thursday-was-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattstine.com/2007/05/11/thursday-was-slow/</guid>
      <description>for me, not for JavaOne. Of course I was a good little programmer and used the schedule builder to sign up for all of my sessions. I edited them a bit after the first two keynotes. Even then, I had one lone session scheduled for Thursday morning (that wasn&amp;rsquo;t really directly applicable to my work, it just looked interesting), and then two sessions in the afternoon, the first starting at 4:10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wednesday was ajax day</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstine.com/2007/05/10/wednesday-was-ajax-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattstine.com/2007/05/10/wednesday-was-ajax-day/</guid>
      <description>Not officially, but nearly every session I attended had something to do with AJAX:
 Creating Amazing Web Interfaces with Ajax
 jMaki: Web 2.0 App Building Made Easy
 Fast, Beautiful, Easy: Pick Three - Building Web User Interfaces in the Java Programming Language with Google Web Toolkit
 Killer JavaScript Technology Frameworks for Java Platform Developers: An Exploration of Prototype, Script.aculo.us, and Rico
  I have to say that I was rather impressed by what I saw.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>