<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ruby | Matt Stine</title>
    <link>https://www.mattstine.com/categories/ruby/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.mattstine.com/categories/ruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>ruby</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Matt Stine</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>ruby</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstine.com/categories/ruby/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>practical jruby on rails web 20 projects</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstine.com/2008/01/25/practical-jruby-on-rails-web-20-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mattstine.com/2008/01/25/practical-jruby-on-rails-web-20-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are Java&#39;s days numbered as a web development technology? With buzzwords like Ruby, Rails, and Web 2.0 zipping around the web development community, one may begin to wonder. Could Java&#39;s lifespan be extended by finding synergy between Java and Ruby? On the scene comes JRuby, the definitive implementation of Ruby for the JVM. In his new book from Apress, Ola Bini guides the reader through the development of four Web 2.0 projects using JRuby on Rails. I think that Bini does a masterful job of always using the right tool for the right job. &lt;a href=&#34;http://java.dzone.com/reviews/practical-jruby-rails-web-20-p&#34;&gt;Read my review for complete details.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>thursday was slow</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstine.com/2007/05/11/thursday-was-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mattstine.com/2007/05/11/thursday-was-slow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;for me, not for JavaOne. Of course I was a good little programmer and used the schedule builder to sign up for all of my sessions. I edited them a bit after the first two keynotes. Even then, I had one lone session scheduled for Thursday morning (that wasn&#39;t really directly applicable to my work, it just looked interesting), and then two sessions in the afternoon, the first starting at 4:10. I decided to skip out on the morning session and do a little shopping at Pier 39. The highlight was a &amp;ldquo;Bucket of Boat Trash&amp;rdquo; and clam chowder at the Bubba Gump Shrimp Company. And yes, we Ole Miss Rebels are represented as far out as the end of Pier 39:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/matt.stine/SanFranciscoJavaOne2007/photo#5063511710562298018&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://lh4.google.com/image/matt.stine/RkU1ErgYqKI/AAAAAAAAAMA/6BJ0mkhqgn8/s288/DSCN1117.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two sessions that I attended were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RubyTooling: State of the Art&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Ajax with POJC (Plain Old JavaServer Faces Components)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attended the first session simply to get a little more detail on all of the hype surrounding Ruby tooling support in NetBeans 6. What I got was even more than I bargained for. The project leaders actually walked us through not only the features that were available, but how they were implemented. I had never really thought about the problems with providing code completion and refactoring with a dynamically-typed language. It was really cool to see the thought process that went into their solutions. I&#39;d love to hear a similar discussion from the JetBrains guys, as the Ruby support in IntelliJ IDEA is quite good as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me the second session was the best of the conference for me up until that point, and arguably it still is after attending Friday&#39;s sessions. Craig McClanahan, of Struts fame, was the main speaker and was joined by his colleagues Matthew Bohm and Jayashri Visvanathan. What made this session so good for me was that they presented a problem - &amp;ldquo;How can I add Ajax behaviors to my JavaServer™ Faces technology based application, without throwing away my investment in existing component libraries?&amp;rdquo; - and then provided three different solutions to that problem - low, medium, and high level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The low level consisted of simply using the HTML event pass-through attributes that are implemented by most standard JSF components (onClick, onBlur, etc.). One could use an existing JavaScript framework such as Dojo to send an XMLHttpRequest and then map that request to a Servlet or JSF handler using a technology such as Shale Remoting. The response could be sent back as JSON data which could then be transformed into the desired UI update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The medium level consisted of actually extending existing JSF components and adding the desired Ajax behavior. Due to time constraints they didn&#39;t cover this solution in detail, but they did provide a link to a detailed discussion in the Java BluePrints catalog: &lt;a href=&#34;https://blueprints.dev.java.net/bpcatalog/ee5/ajax/extendingRenderFunctionality.html&#34;&gt;https://blueprints.dev.java.net/bpcatalog/ee5/ajax/extendingRenderFunctionality.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The high level solutions addressed the following needs (copied directly from the slides):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;● Partial page submit—gather up a particular set of&lt;br&gt;
input element values, and send them to a bit of server&lt;br&gt;
side business logic&lt;br&gt;
● Partial page refresh—the business logic needs to&lt;br&gt;
refresh the content of one or more subtrees of the&lt;br&gt;
client side DOM&lt;br&gt;
● Synchronization—the benefits of synchronizing the&lt;br&gt;
server side state&lt;br&gt;
● Don’t repeat yourself (DRY)—reuse existing&lt;br&gt;
components and renderers for partial page updates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address these issues, the speakers highlighted two add-on frameworks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;● Ajax4JSF (&lt;a href=&#34;http://labs.jboss.com/portal/jbossajax4jsf&#34;&gt;http://labs.jboss.com/portal/jbossajax4jsf&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br&gt;
● Dynamic Faces (&lt;a href=&#34;https://jsf-extensions.dev.java.net/&#34;&gt;https://jsf-extensions.dev.java.net/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was quite impressed with both of these frameworks. One of my colleagues is currently implementing Ajax behavior in a Facelets-based application using Ajax4JSF and he is quite happy with it. Dynamic Faces looked really awesome, especially its tooling support in NetBeans (actually I&#39;m quite impressed with the overall JSF support in NetBeans - I&#39;ll definitely be adding it to my tool belt). The highlight of the presentation was Matt&#39;s video of him building an entire currency trading application in 28 minutes - except it was &amp;ldquo;fast-played&amp;rdquo; to finish in 3 1/2 minutes and set to techno music. Matt wowed us with his dancing abilities while we watched true RAD. The crowd went wild!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>it seems to be the year of the dynamicscripting language</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstine.com/2007/05/08/it-seems-to-be-the-year-of-the-dynamicscripting-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mattstine.com/2007/05/08/it-seems-to-be-the-year-of-the-dynamicscripting-language/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/matt.stine/SanFranciscoJavaOne2007/photo#5062324250889201762&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://lh6.google.com/image/matt.stine/RkD9FbgYqGI/AAAAAAAAALY/NEPT0IawaRY/s288/DSCN1113.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a whirlwind of a day. I&#39;ve been to two keynotes (close to 5 hours of information there) and one technical session. Couple that information with what I heard at Java University yesterday, and you find many common themes. One that keeps coming up is the emerging trend of making other languages, particularly dynamic/scripting languages, first-class citizens on the JVM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Wikipedia, &amp;ldquo;Dynamic programming language is a term used broadly in computer science to describe a class of high level programming languages that execute at runtime many common behaviors that other languages might perform during compilation, if at all. These behaviors could include extension of the program, by adding new code, or by extending objects and definitions, or by modifying the type system, all during program execution. These behaviors can be emulated in nearly any language of sufficient complexity, but dynamic languages provide direct tools to make use of them.&amp;rdquo; This definition seems to fit quite nicely with what I&#39;ve heard the last two days. A couple of dynamic languages I&#39;ve heard A LOT about are Groovy and Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, Ruby and its most popular framework, Ruby on Rails, have survived the initial hype. They are here to stay. Not only that, they seem poised to make a serious impact on the way we will do web application development over the next several years. Sun made a HUGE splash when they decided to hire the core developers of JRuby, the project which in its current pre-1.0 release already runs 98% of Ruby on Rails as a first-class citizen on the JVM. Not only that, you can now create a WAR file from a Ruby on Rails application and deploy it to any Java application server! I&#39;ll write more on this in another entry as I attended a full technical session on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re too uncomfortable getting away from Java, why not try Groovy? After all, it is a JSR (241). All of Java syntax is legal in Groovy, plus a lot more. Groovy is a dynamic scripting language like Ruby and also compiles to bytecode, making it a first-class citizen on the JVM. It has its own MVC framework, Grails (formerly Groovy on Rails), which is a direct competitor to Ruby on Rails. I&#39;ve already written on Groovy and Grails in an earlier entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to attend some additional sessions focused on these dynamic languages, as it seems they will be really important in the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
