<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rails on Matt Stine</title>
    <link>https://www.mattstine.com/categories/rails/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rails on Matt Stine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Matt Stine</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mattstine.com/categories/rails/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>and then it was over</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstine.com/2007/05/11/and-then-it-was-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattstine.com/2007/05/11/and-then-it-was-over/</guid>
      <description>I really enjoyed &amp;ldquo;The Toy Show&amp;rdquo; this morning. James Gosling went through a flurry of different demos from around the &amp;ldquo;cool&amp;rdquo; Java world. I was especially impressed with Project Wonderland (http://lg3d-wonderland.dev.java.net/), a virtual workplace environment, and with the real-time robotics demos. Unfortunately I was so sucked in that I didn&amp;rsquo;t get any good photos.
If anything you could call this my day on the back end. I attended four sessions, two of which were focused on that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>it seems to be the year of the dynamicscripting language</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstine.com/2007/05/08/it-seems-to-be-the-year-of-the-dynamicscripting-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattstine.com/2007/05/08/it-seems-to-be-the-year-of-the-dynamicscripting-language/</guid>
      <description>It has been a whirlwind of a day. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to two keynotes (close to 5 hours of information there) and one technical session. Couple that information with what I heard at Java University yesterday, and you find many common themes. One that keeps coming up is the emerging trend of making other languages, particularly dynamic/scripting languages, first-class citizens on the JVM.
According to Wikipedia, &amp;ldquo;Dynamic programming language is a term used broadly in computer science to describe a class of high level programming languages that execute at runtime many common behaviors that other languages might perform during compilation, if at all.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>