<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ipod | Matt Stine</title>
    <link>https://www.mattstine.com/categories/ipod/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.mattstine.com/categories/ipod/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>ipod</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Matt Stine</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.mattstine.com/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>ipod</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstine.com/categories/ipod/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>my ipod is on rice</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstine.com/2009/03/13/my-ipod-is-on-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mattstine.com/2009/03/13/my-ipod-is-on-rice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let me set the stage for you. I&amp;rsquo;m driving home happily listening to Ted Neward discuss the merits of Scala on the Javaworld podcast. As I pull into the driveway I see my wife waving frantically in the window. As geek brain struggles to process this, home brain kicks into gear. She needs me in the house now! I jump out of the car and slam the door shut, leaving all of the belongings I typically carry in the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enter the house to find that a wasp has some how gotten in and is terrorizing the family. What ensues is roughly 15 minutes of wasp hunting. Wasp dead - end of story. Or so I thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;m driving my iPod (attached to the iTrip FM transmitter/charger) typically sits in my lap (for some reason I get the least FM interference that way). What I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice in my hasty departure from the vehicle is that my iPod nano flew out of the vehicle and was hanging by the iTrip cable. Unaware of this, I slammed the door on the cable and walked away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This in and of itself wasn&amp;rsquo;t a huge problem. Leaving it that way for approximately 24 hours - most of which included rather steady rainfall - was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, a quick Google search finds that the consensus approach seems to be sticking the iPod in a cup of dry rice to soak up the moisture. So there you have it - my iPod is on rice. I hope it works. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
