<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work on Matt Stine</title>
    <link>https://www.mattstine.com/categories/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work on Matt Stine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Matt Stine</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mattstine.com/categories/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>design meeting patterns/antipatterns</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstine.com/2011/05/16/design-meeting-patternsantipatterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattstine.com/2011/05/16/design-meeting-patternsantipatterns/</guid>
      <description>For those of you that don&amp;rsquo;t know, I recently returned to the technical ranks as a Software Architect after a three-year stint in management. To make a long story short, I now love my job again. Perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll write the long story in a future blog entry. On to the topic at hand. Today I led the first significant design discussion that I have led in quite a long time. A few minutes afterward, I was already reflecting on what had occurred and how.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pomodoro the first iteration</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstine.com/2009/11/04/pomodoro-the-first-iteration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattstine.com/2009/11/04/pomodoro-the-first-iteration/</guid>
      <description>I spent about an hour last night reading through Francesco Cirillo&amp;rsquo;s e-book The Pomodoro Technique. Up until this point I knew the basics of the technique, but I really wanted to drill down and get the details. I won&amp;rsquo;t explain those here - visit http://www.pomodorotechnique.com/ to get the lowdown. What I want to talk about is my experience applying the technique this morning.
I managed to complete two Pomodoros. Each of the Pomodoros was filled with internal interruptions of various kinds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>havent had much time to blog lately</title>
      <link>https://www.mattstine.com/2007/08/17/havent-had-much-time-to-blog-lately/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattstine.com/2007/08/17/havent-had-much-time-to-blog-lately/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip;.because we&amp;rsquo;ve been packing to move on top of all of our regular projects. St. Jude has nicely renovated a new building for us, so we developers are moving. This is where I&amp;rsquo;m headed on Monday:
I&amp;rsquo;m both loving it and a little sad - I&amp;rsquo;ve been sitting in my desk for nearly my entire career as a software developer. I just know I&amp;rsquo;m going to park in the garage and come downstairs one morning to find my office gone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>